Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material
  - Stravinsky, Music By
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Chant des batelier du Volga. Chant populaire russe., n.d. (Box 53)
      Manuscript.
      Z 5(M). Not in DSL. Manuscript in L.M.'s hand.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois poesies de la lyrique japonaise (1913) pour chant {soprano}, deux flutes {la 2de-pet. fl.}, deux clarinettes {la 2de-cl. bas.}, piano, deux violons, alto et violoncelle., 2 copies, ostensibly with the same plates but different covers and title pages. (Box 53)
      Texte francaise de Maurice Delage.
      P51(1). DSL has transposed the plate nos. of this edition, R.M.V. 199 and the instrumental score, R.M.V. 200.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Chant des bateliers du Volga (1917) for wind ensemble., 1970. (Box 53)
      Edited by Randall Croley.
      New York: Autograph Editions.
      Z 5(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Une valse pour les petits lecteurs du Figaro., 1922 (Mai).; 2 copies. (Box 53)
      Manuscript (reproduction from transparencies).
      V 2(M). Reproduced in Stravinsky, the composer and his works, by Eric Walter White, p.210.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois Histoires pour enfantes., 1927, 1920. (Box 53)
      Mis en francaise par C.F. Ramuz. English version by Rosa New March.
      H 8(2). Plate no 3830(1), the same as 1920 edition.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Trois] Histoires pour enfants., 1920. (Box 53)
      H 8(1). Same plate no.as 1927 revision. Insert English translation of texts.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Chant des bateliers de Volga. Chant populaire russe., 1920. (Box 53)
      London: J. & W. Chester, Limited [Holograph copy in pencil].
      Z 5(M). Not listed in DSL. Manuscript in L.M.'s hand.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Chant du rossignol [1917] poeme symphonique en trois parties., 1927. (Box 53)
      C14(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois pieces pour clarinette solo (1919)., 1920. (Box 53)
      P34(2). DSL indicates a second, 1923, copyright not present in this edition.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Pieces facile] Five easy pieces (1917) for piano duet (right hand easy). (Box 53)
      P41(2). DSL lists plate no.2909. This is 2909(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Ragtime [1919] pour onze instruments., 1922, 1919. (Box 53)
      Couverture de Pablo Picasso.
      R 2(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Renard (1916) Piano arrangement to replace the Hungarian cimbalum., n.d. (Box 53)
      Manuscript (unknown hand).
      R 7(M).
    - Stravinsky, Igor d'apres Giambattista Pergolesi--[Pulcinella] Scherzino., 1920. (Box 53)
      S65(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor d'apres Giambattista Pergolesi--[Pulcinella] Con queste paroline., 1920. (Box 53)
      P63.5(1). DSL lists the copyright date as 1925.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois poesies de la lyrique japonaise [1913] pour chant (soprano), deux flutes (Los Angeles 2de=fl.[sic]), deux clarinettes (Los Angeles 2de-cl. bas), piano, deux violons, alto et violoncelle. (Box 53)
      Texte francais de Maurice Delage.
      P52(1). DSL omits this plate no.(200) and instead assigns that number (incorrectly) to the contemporaneous piano reduction.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois poesies de la lyrique japonaise (1913) chant et piano., 1947. (Box 53)
      P51(). Plate no.B. & H. 16308. Photo-litho(?) of original edition. [R.M.V. 199]... Cover and title page not reproduced. No English version in original, only Russian & French.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Pieces facile no.4] Napolitana., 1941. (Box 53)
      P42(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Trois pieces pour clarinette] Three pieces for Clarinet [1919]., 1949. (Box 53)
      New York: Omega Music Company.
      P34(). Not listed in DSL.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Ragtime [1919] for eleven instruments., 1920. (Box 53)
      R 2(). The same plates as R2(1), but different copyright, no title page and English title.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--L'Histoire du soldat (1918) Grande Suite., 1922. (Box 53)
      H 4(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Quatre chants russes (1918)., 1920. (Box 53)
      Mis en francais par C.F. Ramuz.
      C18(1). 3 copies in folder marked Four Russian songs, all with plate no.3831 (as in DSL), however one copy appears older with a different cover and title page. Pencil analysis and translation in no.2.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Chant des bateliers du Volga. Chant populaire russe., 1920. (Box 53)
      Z 5(1). Manuscript in L.M.'s hand.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Petrouchka (revised 1947 edition) burlesque in four scenes by Igor Strawinsky and Alexandre Benois., 1948. (Box 53)
      P17(1). DSL misleadingly states arranged by the composer and Alexandre Benois; the ballet is by I.S. and A.B.--the reduction for piano four hands is by the composer.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Piano-Rag-music (1919)., 1920. (Box 53)
      P33(1). This is a later reprint.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Piano-Rag-music (1919)., 1920. (Box 53)
      P33(1). This is the original edition.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Ragtime [1919] pour onze instruments. (Box 53)
      Paris: Editions de la Sirene.
      R 2(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Ragtime (1918) pour onze instruments., 1920. (Box 53)
      R 1(4).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Pulcinella] Suite pour violon et piano (1925) d'apres themes, fragments et morceaux de Giambattista Pergolesi., 1926. (Box 53)
      S33(2). There are two copies. The first in one volume. The second as five separately published movements in a folder labeled Suite pour violon et piano (Pulcinella).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Mavra (1925) ouverture pour piano., 2 copies. (Box 54)
      M 8(). Not listed in DSL, plate no.R.M.V. 411.-411a (1925 Vocal score is R.M.V. 411, essentially the same plate).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Octet] Octuor [1923] pour instruments a vent., 1924. (Box 54)
      O 1(1?). DSL does not distinguish between this large score (plate no.R.M.V. 415) and the small score in Box 40.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Octet] Octuor pour instruments a vent., 1926. (Box 54)
      O 3(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Mavra] [Chanson de Paracha] Russian maiden's song., 1948. (Box 54)
      Lyrics by B. Kochno after A.S. Poushkin. English translation by R. Burness.
      [New York]: Boosey & Hawkes, Incorporated.
      M 7(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Mavra] Chanson [de Paracha] russe (Russian Maiden's Song)., 1951. (Box 54)
      M 6(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Mavra] Chanson [de Paracha] russe (1937)., 1947, 1938. (Box 54)
      London: Boosey & Hawkes, Limited by arrangement with Edition A. Gutheil.
      M 5(2). In L.M.'s hand: Alterations from 'Concert Version' of aria (M 7[a]{}), which already differs from Mavra original throughout piano score in pencil.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Mavra] Chanson de Paracha (1922-23) tiree de l'opera-bouffe Mavra., 1925. (Box 54)
      Texte russe de B. Kochno, d'apres A. Pouchkine. Version francaise par J. Larmanjat. English version by R. Burness. Deutsch von A. Elukhen.
      M 7[a](). Not listed in DSL. Plate no.R.M.V. 458.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Pulcinella] Suite italienne (1932) pour violoncelle et piano., 1934. (Box 54)
      S34(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Serenade en la (1925) en quatre mouvements pour piano., 1947. (Box 54)
      S19(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Concerto (1923-1924) pour piano suivi d'orchestre d'harmonie. (Box 54)
      C36(1). Plate no.R.M.V. 414 (DSL has R.M.V. 1). DSL also omits editor for this edition but not the later Boosey reprint.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Sonate (1924) pour piano., 1925. (Box 54)
      S23(2).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Mavra (1922) Air de la mere pour chant et piano., 1925. (Box 54)
      Opera bouffe en 1 acte d'apres A. Pouchkine. Texte de Boris Kochno. English Version by Robert Burness. Traduction francaise par Jacques Larmanjat.
      M 8[a](). Not listed in DSL, plate no.R.M.V. 411.-411b (1925 vocal score is R.M.V. 411 essentially the same plate).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Serenade en la (1925) en quatre mouvements pour piano., 1926.; Two copies. 1, slightly larger is stamped In die Universal Edition als U.E.-Nr. 8603 aufgenommen. (Box 54)
      S19(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Pater noster (new version with Latin text)., 1949. (Box 54)
      P 8(1[?]). No plate no. DSL lists plate no.1833.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Pater noster (1926)., [1932]. (Box 54)
      P 7(1). Insert, a hand-copied manuscript of this same edition.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Oedipus Rex (1926-1927) opera oratorio en deux actes d'apres Sophocle par I. Strawinsky et J. Cocteau. (Box 54)
      O 7(3[?]). Plate no.R.M.V. 429. DSL lists O7(3) as E.R. de M., 1948,1928,1926, plate no.R.M.V. 431.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Mavra (1922) opera bouffe en 1 acte d'apres A. Pouchkine., 1925. (Box 54)
      English version by Robert Burness. Traduction francaise par Jacques Larmanjat. Deutsche Ubersetzung von A. Elukhen.
      M 4(1). In L.M.'s hand: FS = Str's alterations in full score, pencil marks throughout. Insert p.41 manuscript copy of full score in black and red ink showing variants.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Mavra [1922] Chanson de Paracha pour chant et piano., 1925. (Box 54)
      Text russe de B. Kochno, d'apres A. Pouchkine. Version francaise par J. Larmanjat. English version by R. Burness. Deutsch von A. Elukhen.
      M 7(1). DSL incorrectly reads based on piano vocal score. Plate no.R.M.V. 467. In L.M.'s hand: This is the piano reduction of the voice with orchestra version (reduced orchestra-M 7[a]()-RMV 458).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Sonate (1924) pour piano., 1925.; 2 copies. (Box 54)
      S23(1). One, slightly larger bears an imprint on the cover Imp. Delanchy-Dupre--Paris-Asnieres and in pencil on the title page 5544. The other, blue pencil on the cover 8357.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Concerto [1923-24] pour piano suivi d'orchestre d'harmonie., 1924. (Box 54)
      C34(2). Plate no.R.M.V. 412 (DSL lists 414). In L.M.'s hand: Green pen = alterations in copyist hand in 1936 edition, ERM (RMV 607) but also some printed alterations not in this copy.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois petites chanson (1913-1930) pour petites orchestre., 1934.; Photographic prints 3 × 5. Negatives in green folder. (Box 65)
      P14(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Trois petites chanson., n.d. (Box 65)
      P13(2?). Incomplete photographic prints of original edition. Plate no.R.M.V. 235.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Concerto (1923-24) pour piano et orchestre d'harmonie., 1936.; Photographic prints cut 6.5 × 10.5 pasted back to back (incomplete, pages are missing) with Negatives. (Box 65)
      C34(1).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--L'Histoire du soldat., n.d.; Photographic prints (including some blow-ups) of sketches and Manuscript in author's hand. Inside manila envelope. (Box 65)
      Labeled l'Histoire du soldat.
      H 1().
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Tchaikovsky, P.I. Pas de deux (L'Oiseau bleu--Bluebird) from P. Tschaikowsky's ballet The sleeping beauty., 1953. (Box 70)
      Arranged for small orchestra by Igor Strawinsky.
      Z 4(2). Inscribed in pencil on front cover: To Lawrence Morton IStr January 1st 1955.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Monumentum [1960] pro Gesualdo di Venosa ad CD Annum. (Box 70)
      Recomposed for instruments by Igor Stravinsky.
      M12(1). Inscribed in ink on the title page: To you, my dear Lawrence (Morton) whom I am so happy to meet in Venice Love I. Stravinsky September/60.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Canticum sacrum (1955) ad honorem sancti Marci nominis for tenor and baritone soli, chorus and orchestra., 1956. (Box 70)
      C 5(1). Inscribed in ink on the cover: To Lawrence Morton cordially IStr 1957.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--The flood (1961-62) a musical play., 1963. (Box 70)
      F 7(1). Inscribed in green ink on the cover: R. Craft transfer to L. Morton il vecchio amico.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Persephone (1934, revised 1949) pour tenor, choeur mixte et orchestra. (Box 70)
      Melodrame en trois tableaux d'Andre Gide.
      P10(1). Inscribed in ink on the title page: To Lawrence Morton happy new Year cordially I. Stravinsky Dec/20[1953]. Year added in L.M.'s hand. Insert front cover, postcard of Cieslewicz Persephone.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Bach, Johann Sebastian. Fuga (a 2 voci) & Fuga XI (a 3 voci)., n.d. (Box 71)
      [Arranged for instruments by Igor Stravinsky].
      Reproduction from transparencies in Stravinsky's hand and that of a copyist.
      ZZ 8(M). Not listed in DSL.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--The owl and the pussycat [1966]., Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 71)
      O42(M). Inscribed: To Lawrence Morton cordially October/66.
    - Stravinsky, Igor-- andantino from Eight instrumental miniatures., 1962 (April).; (Photographic print 8 × 10). (Box 71)
      I 3(M). Original is inscribed Dear Lawrence (Morton) Keep this page as a souvenir of your friend who dedicated the whole suite of this `Eight instrumental Miniatures' to you Yours as ever I. Stravinsky Apr.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Variations (1963-64) Aldous Huxley in memoriam., 1965. (Box 71)
      V 3(2). Plain grey wrapper signed L. Morton in blue ink and IStr March 25/65 in red ink.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Four Songs (1918, instr. 1953) for voice, flute, harp & guitar., 1955. (Box 71)
      S25(1?). Plate no.J.W.C. 3831A. DSL lists plate no.3831 only. On title page: To Lawrence Morton and his wonderful musicianship IStr /55 in red ink.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Abraham and Isaac (1962-63) for baritone and chamber orchestra., 1963. (Box 71)
      Reproduced and bound from transparencies by Cameo Music Reproduction.
      A 1(M). Insert inside front cover, Original and Inverse forms of the row divided into hexachords by vertical lines.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Abraham and Isaac (1962-63) a sacred ballad for baritone and chamber orchestra., 1965. (Box 71)
      A 2(1). Inscribed in black felt pen on title page: To Lawrence Morton with love from I. Stravinsky April 11 / 65.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Berceuses du chat [1916] suite de chants pour une voix de femme et trois clarinettes., 1917. (Box 71)
      Geneve: Ad. Henn.
      B14[1]. DSL incorrectly gives date as 1923. Inscribed on front cover upper left corner: To [Cyrillic](Lawrence Morton) with authentic affection Igor Stravinsky 'Morges 1917'.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--J.S. Bach: Choral variationen uber das weinachtslied Vom Himmel hoch dakomm ich her., 1956.; Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 71)
      Z 1(M). Inscribed in upper right hand corner front cover: To Lawrence Morton with affectionateness I. Str Easter /56.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Elegy for J.F.K. (1964)., 2 copies. Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 71)
      Text by Wystan Auden.
      E 5(M). On one, red pencil corrections and insert--original and inversion form ofrow.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Praeludium., 1937. (Box 71)
      Unpublished.
      P55(M). Insert-photostat of 1937 orchestration (with strings) and two sheets from transparencies in L.M.'s hand: To replace the original string guitar and timp. section on p.8.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--In memoriam Dylan Thomas (1954) dirge canons and song for tenor voice string quartet and four trombones. (Box 71)
      I 1(2). Insert Manuscript trombone parts. Inscribed on title page: To you, dear Lawrence (Morton)cordially I. Str October 54.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Eight instrumental miniatures (1962)., 2 complete copies. Reproduction from transparencies. (Box 71)
      I 3(). Insert in bound green copy--separate leaf copies of Andantino, Vivace, Lento and Allegretto.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Agon (1954-1957) ballet for twelve dancers., Reproduction from transparencies. (Box 71)
      A 3(M). Inscribed on p.1 in upper right corner: To Lawrence Morton all best cordially Igor Stravinsky June /57.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Elegy for J.F.K. (1964)., Manuscripts. In large envelope. (Box 71)
      Labeled Stravinsky: Elegy for J.F.K. These are the three clarinet parts used at the first performance.
      E 5(M).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Anthem (1962) The dove descending breaks the air for chorus a cappella. (Box 71)
      D 5(1). Inscribed: To you, dear Lawrence yours as ever I. Str March 2 /64.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--[Balmont songs] The flower & The dove [for soprano and chamber orchestra]., 1954.; Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      P50(M).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Requiem canticles (1966)., Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      R 9(M).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--The flood [1962]., n.d.; Reproduction from transparencies. (Box 72)
      F 7(M). Insert front cover an elaborate serial analysis including a leaf with the series of Schoenberg's Begleitmusik. In L.M.'s hand, pencil analysis in many colors throughout. F 8(1) included.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--A sermon, a narrative and a prayer (1960-61) for solo voices, recitation, and chorus with instruments., Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      S20(M). In four parts. Two copies of part 1 (Sermon), one of which is inscribed in the upper left corner of page 1: To Lawrence Morton with affectionate thoughts I. Stravinsky May/61.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Introitus (1965) T.S. Eliot in memoriam. (Box 72)
      I 4(). Large score is not listed in DSL. Plain grey wrapper inscribed in the upper right hand corner: Igor Stravinsky March 22/65.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Eight instrumental miniatures [1962] Andantino. (Box 72)
      I 3(M).
      Photocopy of autographed reproduction from transparencies (See Box 71).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Wolf, Hugo. Two songs from the Spanischer liederbuch [1967]., Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      Z18(M). In L.M.'s hand: I made the full score of the Wolf songs, at S's request, from his sketch-particel.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Hommage a Nadia Boulanger a chanter a son anniversaire, l'an 1947, le jourde 16 septembre, a l'occasion duguel ces vers de Jean de Meung (XIII siecle) furent mis en musique par Igor Stravinsky (XX siecle). (Box 72)
      Unpublished manuscript reproduced from transparencies.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Souvenir d'un marche boche., [1915].; Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      S28(M).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Anthem [1962] The dove descending breaks the air., Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      D 5(M). Complete serial analysis throughout with the four main forms of the row copied on the back page with a schemata of the dispersion of the series to the voices.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Pulcinella ballet mit gesang in einem aufzuf., n.d.; Photographic negatives and proof. (Box 74)
      Nach italienischen szenarien bearbeitet von Prof. James Bloch.
      P58a().
    - Pas D'aggrandissement., Photographic negatives and prints. (Box 74)
      ZZ11(). Orchestration of Russian song (negatives of manuscript).
    - [Stravinsky] Works: Etude for Pianola, Valse pour les enfants, Beethoven opus 75/3 [Orchestration], Souvenir d'une Marche boche., n.d.; Photographic negatives, proofs and prints. (Box 74)
      ZZ12(). Miscellaneous.
    - Le Sacre du Printemps--pages from plate no.RMV 197b (L. of C.)., n.d..; Photographic 3 × 5 prints. (Box 74)
      S 1(1). Incomplete.
    - Moussorgsky-Stravinsky, The Flea., n.d.; Photographic prints. (Box 74)
      Z13(M). Three sets of prints of the orchestral score.
    - Beethoven, Marche Boche, F.I. Stravinsky. Mussorgsky-Stravinsky Leagues of Composers programs I (Indoor shots). Gorodetzky no.2. Contact prints completion of Souvenirs de mon enfance. Credo (original) Gorodetsky songs (various editions) Library of Congress Microfilm., Photographic negatives and microfilms. (Box 75)
      Sacre--pages from 197b, errata sheet for 197b. Extra pages--German articles Bruges--beginning of Souvenir de mon enfance; contact prints.
      ZZ10(). Miscellaneous compositions.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Greeting prelude (1955)., Reproduction from transparencies. (Box 82)
      G 1(). Inscribed across the first page To my dear friend Lawrence Morton cordially I. Stravinsky.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Ebony concerto (1945)., Reproduction from transparencies. (Box 82)
      E 1(). Inscribed in ink in upper right hand corner To Gilbert Grau cordially IStr.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Circus Polka (1942) composed for a young elephant., 1943. (Box 102)
      Arranged for violin and piano by Sol Babitz.
      Inscribed on cover: To Lawrence Morton affectionately Sol Babitz 9/12/43.
  - Stravinsky, Music Relating to
    - Juskiewicz, Reverend Anton--Melodie ludowe litewskie (Simple Lithuanian folk songs)., 1900. (Box 8)
      Translated by Birute Lembergas (in manuscript).
      Krakau: Verlag der Polinischen Akademie der Wissenshaft.
      Translation of the individual songs on separate sheets. Work is photocopy of original, unbound. Includes letters regarding arrangement (by L.M.) for the translation.
    - Grieg, Edvard--Lyrische Stucke fur pianoforte opus 7., 1950. (Box 42)
      Frankfurt: C.F. Peters.
    - Mussorgsky, Modeste--The flea lied des Mephistopheles im Auerbach's keller., 1934. (Box 42)
      Moscow: Edition de Musique de L'stat R.S.F.S.R.
    - Mussorgsky, Modeste--The flea., 1911. (Box 42)
      Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel.
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van--Sechs lieder., n.d. (Box 42)
      London: Augener & Company.
    - Wolf, Hugo--Spanisches liederbuch, nach Paul Heyse und Emanuel Geibel. Band I geistlichelieder original ausgabe. (Box 48)
      Englische Ubersetzung von John Bernhoff.
      Stravinsky orchestrated no.IX Herr, was tragt der Boden hier and no.X Wunden tragst du, mein Geliebter in 1968.
    - Wolf, Hugo--Spanisches liederbuch, nach Paul Heyse und Emanuel Geibel. Band III originalausgabe. (Box 48)
      Englische ubersetzung von John Bernhoff.
      Insert photocopy of no.X Wunden tragst du, mein geliebter, from volume 1.
    - Debussy, Claude--43 songs for voice and piano (high)., 1961. (Box 48)
      In L.M.'s hand, red ink identification of poets in the table of contents.
    - Schumann, Robert--Samtliche lieder fur eine singstimme mit klavier begleitung. Band 1-3. Original ausgabe (hohe stimme). (Box 48)
    - Wolf, Hugo--Michelangelo-lieder., n.d. (Box 48)
      In L.M.'s hand, penciled timings and instrumental indications throughout.
    - Lombardo, Carmen--'Round my heart., 1932.; 3 copies. (Box 58)
      Words by Joe Young.
      New York: Famous Music Corporation.
    - Robison, Willard--'Round my old deserted farm., 1937. (Box 58)
      New York: Irving Berlin Incorporated.
    - Burton, Steven--Stravinskiana Concertino for flute and piano., 1975. (Box 71)
    - Spies, Claudio--LXXXV: Eight + fives for strings and clarinets., 1967.; Manuscript reproduced from transparencies. (Box 72)
      Inscribed in upper right corner: For Bob, a brief antidote to CARDILLANGWEILE-Claudio 3. VII.1967.
    - Klebe, Giselher--Surge aquile; et veni, auster: Paraphrase uber ein thema von Igor Strawinskyfur Orgel opus 60., 1972. (Box 72)
      Kassel: Barenreiter-Ausgabe.
    - Beer, Leopold--Marschepperlin., 1946. (Box 73)
      Bearbeitet von Leopold Beer. Band I & II.
      Wien-Leipzig: Musikverlag Johann Kliment.
    - Detskie pesno na russkie i malorossooskie napevy s akkompanimentom fortepiano., [19--?]. (Box 73)
      Mamontovoi pod redaktsieiu Professora P. Chaikovskago, s prilozheniem tekh-zhe pesen vtrekhgolosnom perelozhenii K. Al'brekhta.
      V Moskva: P.I. Urgeneson.
      Russian folk music.
    - Balakirev, M.--Recueil de chants populaires russes, notes et harmonises. Sbornik russkikhnarodnykh p'esen'., 1898. (Box 73)
      Traduction francaise de J. Sergennois.
      Leipzig: M.P. Belaieff.
    - Liapounow, S., arranger--35 chants populaires russes. Pesen' russkago naroda: dlia odnogogolosa s soprovozhdeniem fortepiano iz sobrannykh v 1893 g., 1899. (Box 73)
      S.M. Liapunovym i Th. M. Istominym. Perelozhil S. Liapu November.
      Izsano s vysochaishago soizvoleniia Piesennoiu Komissieuir Imperatorskago Russkago Geograficheskago Obshchestva. [No imprint].